

# Matthew Ewan-Laws

**React Developer** 

#### EXPERIENCE

# Web Developer HR GO Recruitment

06/2019 - 07/2020

I was part of the team to build a React web application that would integrate with an existing Umbraco ASP.NET website. I used Microsoft Azure B2C to provide the authentication and authorisation service.

One challenge of this project was the fact it integrated with a very different technology. I built a custom Webpack solution that allowed us to develop the React app independently but then integrated itself with the existing Umbraco CMS.

Another challenge was one of the REST APIs we were consuming. I found it was often very important to leave comments explaining the various nuances we came across.

For this job I worked with a tightly knit team, which allowed me to develop communication skills.

During this role I also learnt a great deal about the recruitment business.

# Web Developer

SpaceBetween

04/2018 - 06/2018

I worked to create a React front end for a members' area that interfaced with Azure AD B2C authentication and authorisation. The app would integrate with an existing Umbraco website.

#### **Fullstack Web Developer**

The E-Commerce Workroom

08/2016 - 03/2018

I worked as a full stack JavaScript/React developer, for over a year I was one of the two lead developers for a large travel search and booking application.

The stack used was: Meteor.js, JavaScript, React, Mongo, Apollo (GraphQL).

I faced many design challenges during the development process of this application. Notably: caching live data from a REST API so that it is suitable to be used as a searchable data store.

I attended multiple meetings to communicate the technical details, make suggestions and ultimately try to meet the business requirements of the stakeholders.

- +44 (0) 7807919409
- matt.ewanlaws@gmail.com
- https://mdel-web-dev.ml
- Margate, UK

#### SUMMARY

React Developer with 2 years experience, experience with JavaScript, Node.js, CSS. My ambition is to continue as working to create competitive and useful products, to progress in my skills and knowledge to become a stronger and more versatile developer.

### SKILLS

React.js Advanced

JavaScript Advanced

Git Intermediate

CSS Intermediate

HTML Advanced

Node.js Intermediate

Linux Intermediate

PhotoShop Intermediate

### LANGUAGES

English Native

## **EDUCATION**

Computer Science University of Plymouth 2016 BSc

IT Practitioner Kent College 2011 BTEC National Diploma (MMM, A-level eqv of BBB)